Welcome to the Hand Hygiene and
Garbing Lab demonstration video.
The compounder has removed outer
garments, jewelry.
If you have long hair, pull it
back.
You want to be makeup free free
of nail Polish and artificial
nails.
The best practice is to hand
sanitize prior to each step of
the garbing process.
As you step over the line of
demarcation from The Dirty side
to the clean side of the
anteroom, you'll Don that first
shoe cover.
You want to slip the larger end
of the shoe cover into the toe
of the shoe and then pull the
bottom over the shoe onto the
heel.
Notice that the compounder is
hand sanitizing between each
time that they Don the shoe
covers.
Now that we're on the clean side
of the anteroom, hand sanitize.
Now place the bouffant style cap
or head cover over your head so
that most of the hair is in the
back.
Cover the skin on your forehead.
Tuck in any loose hairs.
Hand sanitize with a 70% IPA rub
and then Don the face mask.
Put the top of the mask to the
bridge of the nose and gently
pinch the aluminum strip woven
into the mask.
Position the loops around your
ears.
Make sure you tuck in any of
your hair and now we will
prepare for hand washing.
Welcome to the hand washing
portion of hand hygiene and
garbing procedure.
Take the time to review the step
by step actions you must follow.
During this hand washing
procedure.
We will focus on the hand
washing part of the procedure.
So far we have donned our shoe
covers, our bouffant style cap
or head cover, our face mask,
and now we will prepare to hand
wash before we open the sterile
surgical scrub sponge.
The compounder will squeeze the
packet several times to activate
the soap sets.
The compounder will activate the
automatic sensor to begin the
water flow throughout the entire
hand washing.
Open the package of the surgical
scrub and you'll place the nail
cleaner so that you can clean
under each of your fingernails.
Be sure to position the nail
pick so that you don't
contaminate the sponge with
debris from your fingernails,
and we'll continue.
On the other hand, when
finished, you can discard the
nail cleaner in the waste
container.
Do not use the brush side of the
sponge.
Per USP 797, we'll use the
sponge side to clean all four
surfaces of each finger, the
top, the side, the bottom, and
the side.
And then we'll clean the webbing
and then the top, the bottom the
side the webbing, the top side
the bottom the webbing, the top
the side the bottom the side and
the webbing, the top the side
the bottom the side.
And then we'll switch hands,
clean the top of the thumb, the
side, the bottom the side, Get
the webbing.
Clean the top of your
forefinger, the side, the bottom
the side, the webbing the top
the side, the bottom the side,
the webbing, the top the side,
the bottom the side, the
webbing, the top the side, the
bottom the side.
And now we'll do the palm of
each hand cleaning from the
fingers to the wrist.
We'll clean the palm of the
other hand from the fingers to
the wrist.
Next, you will clean the back of
the hand, focusing on the
knuckles from the fingers to the
wrist.
We'll clean the back of the
other hand.
You can get a small amount of
water if you don't have enough
soap suds.
Finally, we'll clean from the
wrist to the elbow of our
forearm, going in circular
motion around the arm until you
reach the elbow.
You can put your sponge
momentarily in the water to get
more soap sets.
We'll start at the wrist of our
other arm, and we'll clean that
forearm in circular motion,
going all the way around the arm
until we get to the elbow, and
then you can throw that sponge
away with your fingers pointing
up.
We're going to take a pass
through the water.
Take a moment to rinse.
Notice that those fingers are
pointing up.
The compounder is looking at all
the sides of the arm all the way
to the elbow.
If you see any soap sets, go
ahead and do another pass
through the water and then we'll
rinse the other hand fingers up.
Take a moment and clean off the
fingers and gradually move to
your elbow.
Take another look to see if
there's any remaining soap
scents.
Take one more pass and then we
will take a sterile, lint free
wiper and we want to pat the
hand all the way to the elbow.
We're going to pat dry.
We'll get another sterile, lint
free towel and we'll pat the
hand all the way to the elbow.
We have just completed the
aseptic hand washing.
The compounder will Don the
sterile gown.
Take the gown out of the outer
packaging and place it on the
work surface and when you unwrap
the gown, you want to turn the
gown and hold the gown by the
shoulders.
Make sure that the gown doesn't
touch the floor and as you hold
the shoulder you can put each
sleeve on and then you can
position the Velcro across your
neck and with the other hand you
can reach that section of the
Velcro insecure.
And you want to tuck that left
side of the gown.
You want to tuck that in first
and then you want to bring the
right side of the gown around
your body and that tie you can
hand to yourself and make a nice
bow here.
And you want to be tucked into
your gown so that it doesn't
come apart when you get to the
hood.
Now we can hand sanitize our
hands and we're ready to go into
the buffer room.
We will finish the hand hygiene
and garbing procedure by donning
our powder free sterile gloves.
Open the outer wrapper of our
sterile gloves and discard the
packaging.
Open the inner gloves.
Ensure that you don't touch the
gloves with your bare hands.
Per USP 797 will apply an
alcohol based hand rub to all
surfaces of the hands.
You'll pull the sleeve of your
gown holding onto the cuff.
With your thumb and forefinger
you'll grasp the fold of the
cuff and pull it over the hand.
Don't adjust the cuff quite yet.
And then we will pull the sleeve
of our opposite hand, and by the
cuff we'll pull that glove over
the hand.
And now we can adjust the cuffs.
We can discard that inner
packaging and per USP 797, you
must sanitize your hands with
sterile isopropyl alcohol.